The next thing that we want to do is take that matrix
下一步我们将创建该矩阵
and essentially return back. The end goal is this.
并返回矩阵这是最终目标
We want to create a dictionary of movie scene
我们将创建一个字典 movies_seen
where the key is the user and the value
键是用户
is a list or some array of the movie ID.
值是电影 ID 列表或数组
So it could be a list or a NumPy array
它可以是一个列表或 NumPy 数组
or could be a set, but that's the goal.
还可以是一个集合
So essentially, I suggest maybe using
建议创建一个辅助函数
a helper function that just gets the movies
它可以获取
watched for any particular ID given.
任何给定 ID 对应的已看过电影
Again, I like pulling things out and looking
我喜欢提取出数据
at what they do with just one example.
看看有哪些数据 并查看一个示例
So let's take a look at the header of that function.
看看该函数的标题
So you can see this is a very sparse matrix,
这是一个很稀疏的矩阵
and by sparse, I mean it just has NaNs everywhere.
到处都是 NaN
But if we just pull one or we pull two or anything like that,
如果我们提取出用户 1 或用户 2 的数据
it gives us back an array across all the movies.
它会返回一个包含所有电影的数组
So on the rows or all the IDs,
每行都是 ID
on the columns are all the movies.
每列都是电影
So this is the rating for user two across all of the movies,
这是用户 2 对所有电影的评分
and you can see basically for everything we can see it's NaN.
几乎都是 NaN
They just haven't rated a lot of movies.
他们还没有对很多电影评分
One thing that we can do is if we're going
如果要提取
to pull the movies that they've watched,
用户看过的所有电影
we want to look at which ones are null and which ones are not.
我们需要看看哪些为 null 哪些不是
So if we do something like this,
对于这部分
this is null gives back an array of true and falses.
这个 isnull() 会返回一个 true/false 数组
So isnull says if this is true,
如果返回 true
then there was a null value there and otherwise there wasn't.
则表明这里是 null 值 否则不是
If it say it's false and we actually pull the user
如果返回 false
by movie values for that particular user.
那么提取该用户的 user_by_movie 值
So let's do something like this.
代码是这样的
So then basically, this is just saying return
它的作用是
the index that is the movies and return those values.
返回这些电影的索引并返回这些值
So that gives us this array, which is nice.
结果是这样的数组 不错
This part here instead of being two is just
将这里的 2
whatever user ID they pass to us.
替换成传入的 user_id
So you give us a user ID, we'll go in,
提供用户 ID 后
we'll find out which movies this user has
我们将查看此用户评过分的电影
rated and then return that back into this movie's thing,
然后将返回结果存储到这个 movie 变量中
and then we'll give that back to you.
并返回结果
Then the goal here in the next part,
下一部分的目标是
is basically to loop through this function
遍历这个函数
and get a dictionary called movie scene that basically has
获取一个叫做 movies_seen 的字典
this array as the value and the user as the key.
值是这个数组 键是用户
This again will take a little bit of time,
这里运行时间较长
and so I set up a progress bar to do it,
我设置了一个进度条
but really all you need to do is create your dictionary.
而你只需创建该字典
The main thing we want to do is we want to create our dictionary.
我们的主要任务是创建字典
This is where we're going to store things.
将结果存储到此变量中
I also created something called end users,
我还创建了 n_users
which is equal to the number of rows.
它等于行数
So it's just the number of users in our dataset.
表示数据集中的用户数量
I just use that to figure out how I was going to loop for User 1,
我将使用它创建循环
is what I call them in range one through, n users plus 1.
for user1 in range(1:n_users+1);
What we want to do is,
我们将使用
we're going to use our movies scene as the dictionary,
movies_seen 作为字典
and what I want to do is,
我将传入 user1
I want to take User 1 and I want to equate it to movies watched, User 1.
使其等于 movies_watched(user1)
So this is basically all you have to do.
你只需完成这些步骤
If you look at the solution,
如果你查看解答 notebook
I added a progress bar so that I could see what was happening.
会发现我添加了一个进度条 目的是看看代码运行情况
Progress bars are something that I actually use
我多次使用了进度条
quite a few times and range.
哦 这里出错了
So if you set it up correctly,
如果你设置正确的话
you should see your progress bar show up here,
应该会在这里看到进度条
and then you'll see equals signs as they run
当系统遍历每个用户并计算时
through each of the users and calculate things.
这里会出现百分比
This will take a reasonably substantial time to run.
这部分的运行时间很长
So it's important that you are careful
需要注意的是
about whether you use loc or iloc.
这里使用 loc 还是 iloc
If you use iloc, these will need to be different,
如果使用 iloc 这里要改一下
which is why mine broke.
我的代码因为这个错误而崩溃了
So I'm going to go ahead and start this again.
我将重新运行代码
So at the end of this,
运行此单元格后
we now have this movie scene which holds a dictionary,
我们现在获得了存储字典的 movies_seen
where each key is our user ID and the values is the array.
该字典的键是用户 ID 值是数组